Robert Huo

Mobile: 0450 950 778

E-mail: roberthuomelbourne@gmail.com
LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/robert-da-huo/

My site: https://www.devhuo.com/

Summary

- Three years of practical experience in developing complex, high profile Commercial projects in Agile/Scrum team as a full stack developer.
- Specialized in JavaScript, React.js, Node.js, APIs and MongoDB to deliver testable, maintainable, and reusable code.
- A clear, concise, and effective team player in teamwork.
- Adaptable, self-motivated, enthusiastic developer with positive attitude and Great analytical and problem solving abilities, maintaining a high level of efficiency under high pressure.
- Practical knowledge of web development technologies, and always willing to learn and develop new technical skills.

Skills

Front-end: HTML5, CSS3, SASS/LESS, Bootstrap4, Flexbox, JavaScript(Vanilla,

ES6+), jQuery, Pug, Responsive Design, React.js(SPA), Redux.js, Redux-saga, Redux-thunk, DvaJS, Material-UI, Ant-design, Moment.js,

TypeScript, UmiJS, Styled-Component

Back-end: Node.js, Express.js, KeystoneJS, JWT, Helmet, Java, Python

API: RESTful API, GraphQL(Apollo), WebSocket API, Swagger, JSON, Ajax,

axios

Database: MySQL, MongoDB, Mongoose

Tools: Visual Studio Code, Postman, Git, Github, BitBucket, JIRA, Trello, NPM,

Webpack, Babel, ESLint, WordPress, Jest, Enzyme, Zeplin

Cloud Services: AWS Route 53, AWS Amplify, Heroku

Methodologies: Agile/Scrum/Kanban, TDD

Experience

Full-stack developer

Nov 2019 - Current

JR Academy, Remote

- https://learn.jiangren.com.au
- https://jiangren.com.au
- Tech stack: HTML5, CSS3, Less, SASS, JavaScript(ES6 +), React, React-router, Redux, Redux-saga, UmiJs, DvaJs, Ant Design, Pug, Bootstrap, Node.js, KeystoneJS, Express, RESTful API, Swagger, MongoDB, Mongoose, momentjs, NPM, Git, BitBucket, JIRA, Postman, Zeplin, webpack, babel, eslint, prettier.
- Worked with an Agile team, implemented a server-side rendered company website and an online learning dashboard used by students and mentors based on MERN Stack(MongoDB, Express, ReactJS, Node.JS), HTML template engine Pug and Sass, used Git and Bitbucket for version control.

- Tasks: Managed states by Redux-saga, Designed RESTful APIs and implemented CRUD nodejs server, building responsive webpages and scalable user interface based on the Zeplin UI design, managed data-flow using network, refactored existing code from commonJS to ES6, implemented main functions of dashboard including signing up for courses, checking assignments with attached materials left by teachers, listing students' submissions to the teacher and course link managements, sent notification emails by using nodemailer, adjusted webpack configurations to get a better performance, manipulated mongodb database by using mongoose.
- Bugfix: Fixed data flow and UI, managed LocalStorage to store correct data, fixed responsive pages, fixed and improved double sided data binding.

Web developer

May 2018 – Oct 2019

Kinly Beauty, Melbourne

- As a part-time developer, maintained and designed existing website to a responsive and user-friendly website, developed a brand new website by using Wordpress.
- Renewed company information and relevant materials.
- Fixed css styles to meet the design pattern requirements.
- Implemented simple SEO managements.

Software developer

Oct 2015 - Feb 2016

IBM China, Dalian China

- Written in Java, Javascript, HTML, CSS, the project was developed for Coco Cola and P&G.
- Made unit test and black box test.
- Worked in an Agile team, Organized and communicated team agenda, prepared test plan and cases.

Selected Projects

Weather App (https://weather-inquire.netlify.com/)

- Has business project potential.
- Followed High cohesion & Low coupling principle to build a weather inquire APP including adding favourite cities function and single sign-on application by using ReactJS and Redux-thunk.
- Back-end written in Node.js(express), deployed on Heroku, frontend deployed on Netlify.
- Friendly designed UI, which could be reused easily.

Warhammer Player Community (https://warhammer-community.netlify.com/)

- Business project used for warhammer players social contact.
- Back-end implemented by Node.js(Express), deployed on Heroku, used nodemailer to send contact forms to back-end.
- Friendly designed UI, which could be reused easily, written in ReactJS, React Bootstrap, React-Router.

Pizza-Online-order (https://pizza-online-order.netlify.com/)

- Business project used for online pizza order.
- Implemented input validations including email format, email confirmation functions By using ReactJS.
- Back-end deployed on Heroku, which sends user's info and pizza info to chef

through email.

Simplified UI with input validators, which could keep users making valid input.

Personal Blog(https://www.devhuo.com/)

- Deployed on AWS(Amplify & Route 53).
- Implemented user-friendly responsive pages and mobile devices pages by ReactJS, React-Router, and Antd.
- Embraced current tech-trend such as hooks, Sass.
- Implemented language switched function.

Everwell Medical Center Blog(http://everwellmedical.com.au/)

- Maintained and updated a commercial project using wordpress.
- Refactored the existing page by implementing new designed patterns, added new user profiles and managed media.
- Fixed css features on both PC and mobile.
- Used Php and MySQL as back-end.

Education

Master of Information Technology, University of Melbourne, AUSTRALIA Bachelor of Computer Science and Technology, Jilin University, CHINA

Referees

Available upon request